# ALEXIA A. CRAWFORD

# Software Developer M.A.T.

864-363-1977

Portfolio: lexcraw4d.github.io Linkedin: alexiacrawford GitHub: lexcraw4d

## SUMMARY OF SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Apex

Frameworks/Libraries: Node.js, React, MongoDB, Heroku, Jest, GraphQL, jQuery, Inquirer, Bootstrap, Bulma,

Lightning Web Components, Handlebars, Pug.js

Databases/Tools: mySQL, Git/GitHub, GitHub Projects, Mongoose, Sequelize, NoSQL

**Other Skills**: Agile/Scrum, API Development, API consumption, Copado, Session Storage, npm, Local Storage, Subject Matter Expert, Networking B2B/B2C, Ajax, Version Control, TDD, User Authentication, Metadata manipulation and deployment, JWT Authentication, MVC, Lightroom/Photoshop, FERPA/PHI/PPI

# **PROJECTS**

# Helping Hands group project

Helping Hands seeks to serve the less fortunate through grass roots efforts of engaged community members People within their given community are able to collaborate and connect to help others in need

- Role: Backend Developer
- **Tech Stack**: Node.js, JavaScript, Mongoose, JWT Authentication, Handlebars, GraphQL, MongoDB, Heroku
- Links: github.com/lexcraw4d/local-heroes Helping Hands Heroku Deployment

#### **Local Heroes** group project

Users can assist travelers and enhance their traveling experience by connecting them to local individuals that have similar interests

- Role: Backend Developer
- Tech Stack: Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, JWT Authentication, Handlebars
- Links: github.com/lexcraw4d/local-heroes localheroes21.herokuapp.com

#### **Budget Tracker** solo project

Users are able to keep track of individual spendings and earnings throttled both on and offline

- Tech Stack: PWA, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Service Workers
- Links: github.com/lexcraw4d/Budget-Tracker intense-brushlands-65502.herokuapp.com

## Team Profile Generator solo project

Users can generate an automatic html file about their Team by answering prompts within the CLI

- Tech Stack: Javascript, Node.js, Jest, Inquirer
- Links: github.com/lexcraw4d/team-profile-generator

# Weather Dashboard solo project

Users can plan a trip and see weather information at any given location

- Tech Stack: JavaScript, Open Weather API, Postman, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Links: github.com/lexcraw4d/Weather lexcraw4d.github.io/Weather

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Booz Allen Hamilton, Remote

Sept 2021 - Current

#### Web Developer

- Develop code (declarative and programmatic), to assist the team as they continuously enhance and maintain the application, troubleshoot any issues that arise operationally, and upgrade the system to meet security requirements
- Build and integrate Salesforce solutions to change current Veterans Affairs system

- Work both independently and in a team-oriented, collaborative Agile environment
- Obtain and maintain a Public Trust or Suitability/Fitness determination based on client requirements
- Operations and Maintenance development, test, and troubleshooting for Veteran Affair
- Knowledge of code Apex, Lightning Web Components, Visualforce, and Salesforce API to assist the team and continuously enhance and maintain the billable project
- Knowledge of release management solutions such as Jira, and Copado DevOps

## Trilogy Education, Remote

August - Present

Full Stack Assistant Instructor

- Assist Lead Instructor for 24 week Bootcamp at the University of Minnesota.
- Claim and respond to student questions via Slack and respond within reasonable outperforming expectations by yielding productivity 74% higher than average.
- Thoroughly explained conceptual, and general curriculum-based challenges via Slack attaining a perfect student feedback rating.
- Utilize Zoom's "breakout-rooms" feature during activities and in-class projects to assist the students, as needed

# Blackboard, Greenville, SC

Feb 2020 - Oct 2021

**Enrollment Specialist** 

- Communicated effectively via phone, email, and text with prospective and current students.
- Advise students on current & future educational goals.
- Ensures all mandatory prerequisites and admission requirements are met.

# Legacy Early College, Greenville, SC

Jan 2016 - May 2021

Teacher

- Lead grade level meetings centered on best instructional strategies and practices to meet the needs of all students.
- Fostered a positive classroom environment encouraging and promoting student growth.
- Identified skill and knowledge gaps to set realistic goals, resulting in a 100% pass read for end of year evaluations.

CVS, Greenville, SC Feb 2010 - Jan 2016

Lead District Pharmacy Technician (CPhT)

 Recruited, trained and guided 13 stores for Pharmacy Technician Roles which improved overall performance.

# **EDUCATION**

# University of Texas, Austin, TX

Aug 2021

Full Stack Development

- HTML, CSS, Javascript
- Project-based learning
- Weekly and Monthly academic assessments
- OOP, ORM, ODM, MVC, API consumption and development
- Test-Driven Development
- Git and Agile workflows

# Liberty University Lynchburg, VA Masters program

2017 - 2019

Masters of Arts in Teaching

# University of South Carolina Aiken, Aiken, SC, 4 year program

2012 - 2016

B.S. Business Administration and Management

# **Greenville Technical College**, Greenville, SC, Associates program *Associate of Science, Pharmacy Technician*

2010 - 2012